Guide to the James Buchanan Duke Papers, 1777-1999 and undated RL.00001
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Estate Papers, 1777-1934 and undated (bulk 1926-1928); 5
  - Legal Papers, 1777-1928; undated (bulk 1925-1928); 2
    - Claims (allowed): Duke, John Taylor, kinship through: John T. Duke, Lillie I. Duke (affidavits), 1926 (Box 50)
    - Claims (allowed): Duke, Robert, kinship through: Andrew J. Duke, Charles Washington Duke, Eliza Annie Duke (Evans) (Box 50)
    - Claims (allowed): Duke, Robert, kinship through: Robert A. Duke (questionnaires and affidavits), 1926-1928 (Box 50)
    - Claims (allowed): Duke, William J., kinship through: (Executors' questionnaires), 1927 (Box 50)
    - Claims (allowed): Duke, William J., kinship through: James McCadden Duke, William Kirkland Duke, Price (Luena Duke Price) (affidavits), 1926-1927 (Box 51)
    - Claims (allowed): Duke, William J., kinship through: Holloway, Patterson, Lyon (affidavits), 1925-1928 (Box 51)
    - Claims (allowed): Riggs, Amelia Frances Duke, kinship through, 1925-1927 (Box 51)
    - Claims (allowed): Stagg, Mary Duke, kinship through, 1926-1928 (Box 51)
    - Claims (allowed): Fonville, Catherine Roney, kinship through: Executors' questionnaires, 1927 (Box 51)
    - Claims (allowed): Fonville, Catherine Roney, kinship through: affidavits, 1925-1928; 2 folders (Box 51)
    - Claims (allowed): Roney, Amos K., kinship through: Executors' questionnaires, affidavits, 1926-1927 (Box 51)
    - Claims (allowed): Roney, Benjamin F., kinship through: Executors' questionnaires, 1927 (Box 51)
    - Claims (allowed): Roney, Benjamin F., kinship through: affidavits, 1925-1926; 2 folders (Box 51)
    - Claims (allowed): Roney, Calvin Newton Duke, kinship through: Executors' questionnaires, affidavits, 1925-1927 (Box 51)
    - Claims (allowed): Roney, Henry C., kinship through: Executors' questionnaires, 1927 (Box 51)
    - Claims (allowed): Roney, Henry C., kinship through: affidavits, 1925-1926; 2 folders (Box 51)
    - Claims (allowed): Roney, John T., kinship through: Executors' questionnaires, affidavits, 1926-1927 (Box 51)
    - Claims (disallowed): Clinton, Mary, kinship through, 1926-1927 (Box 52)
    - Claims (disallowed): Duke, Alfred Lee, kinship through, 1925-1927 (Box 52)
    - Claims (disallowed): Duke, Clevarious, kinship through, 1926-1927 (Box 52)
    - Claims (disallowed): Duke, Daniel (Virginia), kinship through (Virginia), 1926-1927 (Box 52)
    - Claims (disallowed): Duke, David Washington, kinship through, 1927 (Box 52)
    - Claims (disallowed): Duke, Edmund, kinship through, 1926-1927 (Box 52)
    - Claims (disallowed): Duke, Francis Kirkland, kinship through, 1927 (Box 52)
    - Claims (disallowed): Duke, James, (Sarah E. Duke Osborn), kinship through, 1926-1927 (Box 52)
    - Claims (disallowed): Duke, James, kinship through (Virginia and West Virginia), 1926-1927 (Box 52)
    - Claims (disallowed): Duke, James, kinship through (West Virginia), 1927 (Box 52)
    - Claims (disallowed): Duke, James P., kinship through (Louisiana and Alabama), 1926-1927 (Box 52)
    - Claims (disallowed): Duke, John Taylor, kinship through: Walter Lewis Duke (problem of), 1929 (Box 52)
    - Claims (disallowed): Duke, John Taylor, kinship through: Grief Duke (problem of): includes Duke, Latta, Garrard, Proctor, questionnaires and affidavits, 1925-1927 (Box 52)
    - Claims (disallowed): Duke, Joseph, kinship through, 1926-1927 (Box 52)
    - Claims (disallowed): Duke, Llewellyn/Robert, kinship through, 1925-1927 (Box 52)
    - Claims (disallowed): Duke, Mary Elizabeth, kinship through, 1926-1927 (Box 52)
    - Claims (disallowed): Duke, Polly, kinship through, 1927 (Box 52)
    - Claims (disallowed): Duke, Reany (Reny), kinship through, 1927-1928 (Box 52)
    - Claims (disallowed): Duke, Robert, kinship through, 1926-1927 (Box 52)
    - Claims (disallowed): Duke, Samuel, kinship through, 1925; undated (Box 52)
    - Claims (disallowed): Duke, Tyre or Noah, kinship through, 1925-1927 (Box 52)
    - Claims (disallowed): Duke, William (Durell Mangum), kinship through, 1927 (Box 52)
    - Claims (disallowed): Duke, William (Polly Duke Compton), kinship through (Indiana, Ohio, and Virginia), 1898-1927; 3 folders (Box 52)
    - Claims (disallowed): Duke, William, kinship through (Virginia and Tennessee), 1856-1927; 2 folders (Box 52)
    - Claims (disallowed): Duke, William Edmund, kinship through, 1927 (Box 52)
    - Claims (disallowed): Duke, William J., kinship through (North Carolina), 1925-1927; 5 folders (Box 53)
    - Claims (disallowed): Duke, William J. (John Duke) kinship through, 1926-1927 (Box 53)
    - Claims (disallowed): Duke, William J. (Polly Duke Hardin), kinship through, 1926-1927 (Box 53)
    - Claims (disallowed): Jacobs, Melinda Duke, kinship through, 1926-1927 (Box 53)
    - Claims (disallowed): Roney, kinship through, 1925-1927; 2 folders (Box 53)
    - Claims (disallowed): Roney (Trollinger), kinship through, 1926-1927; 2 folders (Box 53)
    - Claims, miscellaneous: Executors' questionnaires and affidavits, 1872-1927 (Box 53)
    - Item VI Beneficiaries: Assignments: Angier, John, 1926 (Box 53)
    - Item VI Beneficiaries: Assignments: Clute, Grover V., 1928 (Box 53)
    - Item VI Beneficiaries: Assignments: Clute, John H., 1928 (Box 53)
    - Item VI Beneficiaries: Assignments: Fonville, Gabriel L., 1928 (Box 53)
    - Item VI Beneficiaries: Assignments: Garrison, Barbara, 1927-1928 (Box 53)
    - Item VI Beneficiaries: Assignments: Jones, Sallie Colbino, 1927-1928 (Box 53)
    - Item VI Beneficiaries: Assignments: Lyon, W.F., 1927 (Box 53)
    - Item VI Beneficiaries: Assignments: Moore, Martha Ann, 1927-1928 (Box 53)
    - Item VI Beneficiaries: Assignments: Park, Marlowe Roney, 1927 (Box 53)
    - Item VI Beneficiaries: Assignments: Riggs, Frances, 1926-1928 (Box 53)
    - Item VI Beneficiaries: Assignments: Stagg, William L., 1927-1928 (Box 53)
    - Item VI Beneficiaries: Assignments: Wood, Joseph M., 1926-1928 (Box 53)
    - Item VI Beneficiaries: Attachment by the Court of share for Mrs. W.H. (Roxie) Foushee (Wilkinson v. Foushee), 1928-1929 (Box 53)
    - Item VI Beneficiaries: Guardianship: Barton, Essie Lee and Jessie May, 1923-1927 (Box 53)
    - Item VI Beneficiaries: Guardianship: Bowden, Alice M., 1927-1928 (Box 53)
    - Item VI Beneficiaries: Guardianship: Dailey, John Calvin and Lucille Park, 1927 (Box 53)
    - Item VI Beneficiaries: Guardianship: Davis, Henry W., Stanley W., and Montrose J., 1927-1928 (Box 53)
    - Item VI Beneficiaries: Guardianship: Duke, Charles W., 1927-1928 (Box 53)
    - Item VI Beneficiaries: Guardianship: Fonville, Ralph W. and Raymond E., 1927-1928 (Box 53)
    - Item VI Beneficiaries: Guardianship: Holloway, Clarence R., Hallie, Reba, and J. Earl, 1927-1928 (Box 53)
    - Item VI Beneficiaries: Guardianship: Patterson, Victor Hugo, Maurine, and Elbert Earle, 1927-1928 (Box 53)
    - Item VI Beneficiaries: Guardianship: Price, William N., 1927-1928 (Box 53)
    - Item VI Beneficiaries: Guardianship: Roney, Mildred, 1927-1928 (Box 53)
    - Item VI Beneficiaries: Guardianship: Rowland, Mary Florence and Annie Elizabeth, 1924-1928 (Box 53)
    - Item VI Beneficiaries: Guardianship: Wilson, Walter A. and Doris A., 1927-1928 (Box 53)
    - Receipts for Distributions of Assets, Income, and Legacies, and Refunding Bonds, 1926-1934; 4 folders (Box 54)
      Beneficiaries include The Doris Duke Trust, The Duke Endowment, and Nanaline H. Duke
    - Receipts for covering specific bequests (A-Z), 1927-1929; 11 folders (Box 54)
      Item VI beneficiaries
    - Estate of James B. Duke, First Accounting: Petition on First Accounting with schedules, 1926 December 31; 1 Volumes (Box 55)
      Schedules include inventories of assets, stocks, bonds as of October 1925; inventories of personal property at homes in New York, NY, Rough Point, RI, and Myers Park, Charlotte, NC; income to the Estate from October-December 1926; funeral expenses; and administration expenses through December 1926.
    - Estate of James B. Duke, Second and Final Accounting: Petition on Final Accounting with schedules, 1934, April 26; Order Allowing Final Account, 1934, June 15, 1 Volumes (Box 55)
      Schedules include records of income to the Estate and expenses paid by executors since the First Accounting (December 1926)
  - Financial Papers, 1925-1934; 3
    Arranged with the estate's final accounting work papers first (related to Order Allowing Final Account); followed by volumes and records in descending order according to the hierarchy of the bookkeeping system, miscellaneous bookkeeping records, subject files, and banking records. Vouchers and receipts are arranged according to the original schedules of accounting ascribed by the executors.
    Includes final accounting work papers for the estate, a ledger book, journal, cashbooks, trial balances, analysis of income, statements of income, voucher records, vouchers and receipts, and income tax returns. For inventories of James B. Duke's personal properties or receipts for specific bequests granted through his will, see the Legal Papers subseries.
    - Final Accounting work papers, 1925-1934 (Box 55)
    - Final Accounting work papers, 1934-1937 (Box 55)
    - Statements of Distribution of the Estate, 1926-1934 (Box 55)
    - Ledger, 1925-1934; 1 Volumes (Box 56)
    - Journal, 1925 October 11-1934 June; 1 Volumes (Box 56)
    - Cashbook No. 1, 1925 October 16-1932 September 30; 1 Volumes (Box 56)
    - Cashbook No. 2, 1932 October 1-1934 June 18; 1 Volumes (Box 56)
    - Voucher Records No. 1, 1925 October-1930 April; 1 Volumes (Box 57)
    - Voucher Records No. 2, 1930 May-1934 June; 1 Volumes (Box 58)
    - Miscellaneous bookkeeping: Trial Balances, 1925-1934; 10 folders (Box 59)
    - Miscellaneous bookkeeping: Analyses of Income, 1925-1928 (Box 59)
    - Miscellaneous bookkeeping: Statements of Income, 1929 June-December (Box 59)
    - Miscellaneous bookkeeping: Bonds owned by J.B. Duke on 1925, October 10 (Box 59)
    - Miscellaneous bookkeeping: Stocks and bonds, 1925-1933 (Box 59)
    - Miscellaneous bookkeeping: Inventory of office furniture at 535 Fifth Ave., New York, NY, circa 1934 (Box 59)
    - Check stubs: National Bank of Commerce, 1925 October 11-1913 September 28 (Box 59)
    - Check stubs: The National City Bank of New York, 1925 October 11-1928 February 1 (Box 59)
    - Cancelled checks: National Bank of Commerce, 1925-1928 September 13 (Box 59)
    - Cancelled checks: The National City Bank of New York, 1925-1928 September 13 (Box 59)
    - Vouchers and receipts, Administration expenses, 1926 December-1927 February; 3 folders (Box 59)
    - Vouchers and receipts, Administration expenses, 1927 March-1928 September; 11 folders (Box 60)
    - Vouchers and receipts, Administration expenses, 1928 October-1931 June; 16 folders (Box 61)
    - Vouchers and receipts: Administration expenses, 1931 July-1934 June; 15 folders (Box 62)
    - Vouchers and receipts: Bonds/securities delivered to trustees of The Duke Endowment, Trust for Doris Duke, and others, 1928-1933 (Box 63)
    - Vouchers and receipts: Investments and exchanges, 1926-1931 (Box 63)
    - Vouchers and receipts: Property sold, 1927-1931 (Box 63)
    - Vouchers and receipts: Expenses paid from income, 1927-1933 (Box 63)
    - Vouchers and receipts: Collection charges, 1926-1934 (Box 63)
    - Vouchers and receipts: Taxes, 1927-1934 (Box 63)
    - Vouchers and receipts: Debts of decedent, 1927 (Box 63)
    - Vouchers and receipts: Inheritance taxes, 1926-1933 (Box 63)
    - Vouchers and receipts: Executors' fees, 1927-1929 (Box 63)
    - Vouchers and receipts: Liquidation of accounts payable, 1926-1931 (Box 63)
    - Vouchers and receipts: Residuary bequests, 1927-1934 (Box 63)
    - Vouchers and receipts: Distribution of income, 1927-1934 (Box 63)
    - Vouchers and receipts: Miscellaneous, 1927-1931 (Box 63)
    - Bank advices: Bankers Trust Company, Farmers' Loan and Trust Company, Guaranty Trust Company of New York, National Bank of Commerce in New York, 1926 (Box 63)
    - Bank advices: Bankers Trust Company, 1927 (Box 63)
    - Bank advices: Farmers Loan and Trust Co., 1927 (Box 64)
    - Bank advices: Guaranty Trust Company of New York, 1927 (Box 64)
    - Bank advices: National City Bank of New York, 1927 (Box 64)
    - Bank advices: National Bank of Commerce in New York, 1927 (Box 64)
    - Bank advices: Bankers Trust Co., 1928 (Box 64)
    - Bank advices: Farmers Loan and Trust Co., 1928 (Box 64)
    - Bank advices: Guaranty Trust Company of New York, 1928 (Box 64)
    - Bank advices: National Bank of Commerce in New York, 1928 (Box 64)
    - Bank advices: National City Bank of New York, 1928 (Box 64)
    - Bank advices: Guaranty Trust Company of New York, 1929 (Box 64)
    - Bank advices: National Bank of Commerce in New York (Bank of Commerce in New York), 1929 (Box 64)
    - Bank advices: Guaranty Trust Company of New York, 1930 (Box 64)
    - Bank advices: Guaranty Trust Company of New York, 1931-1934 April; 4 folders (Box 64)
    - Passbooks: Central Union Trust Company, 1926-1930; Guaranty Trust Company of New York, 1927-1928 (Box 65)
    - Check stubs: Bankers Trust Company, 1925 November 5-1928 October 4 (Box 65)
    - Check stubs: The Farmers' Loan and Trust Company, 1925 October 11-1928 September 13 (Box 65)
    - Check stubs: Guaranty Trust Company of New York, 1925 October 11-1934 June 18; 2 folders (Box 65)
    - Cancelled checks: Bankers Trust Company, 1925-1928 (Box 65)
    - Cancelled checks: The Farmers' Loan and Trust Company, 1925-1928 September 13 (Box 65)
    - Cancelled checks: Guaranty Trust Company of New York, 1925-1928; 3 folders (Box 65)
    - Cancelled checks: Guaranty Trust Company of New York, 1929-1934; 2 folders (Box 65)
    - Legal and other fees paid, 1928 (Box 65)
    - Federal Income Tax, 1925-1927; 10 folders (Box 65)
    - Federal Income Tax, 1928-1934 (Box 66)
    - Federal Estate Tax, 1931; 1 items (Box 66)
    - State and local taxes: NJ, NY, NC, TX, VA, 1925-1934 (Box 66)
      Includes receipt for New Jersey transfer inheritance tax for Doris Duke (1933)
  - Printed Material, 1925-1926; undated; 4
    Includes publications used by the executors to substantiate their legal case.
    - Handbook of County Records, corrected to Dec. 31, 1924 [NC], 1925 (Box 66)
    - Handwriting Expert Testimony, circa 1920s (Box 66)
    - Confederate Homes and Pensions [public law], circa 1927 (Box 66)
    - Eleventh Biennial Report of the N.C. Historical Commission: December 1, 1924 to November 30, 1926, 1927 (Box 66)
- Miscellaneous, 1898-1999 and undated; 6
  Mainly clippings and printed material related to James B. Duke's life and his businesses, including memorial resolutions and articles. Also contains miscellaneous personal and family items, such as passports, a birth certificate, and tailoring dimensions. A scrapbook that originated after James B. Duke's death contains photographs and clippings related to James B. Duke' s involvement in hydroelectric power and other business and philanthropic interests.
  - General, 1898-1999; undated; 5
    - Biography: Nanaline H. Duke, ca. 1970s; family history, Inman family, undated, circa 1970s (Box 66)
    - Birth certificate, Doris Duke, 1912 (Box 66)
    - Clippings, "The Beginnings of a Trust" [American Tobacco Co.], Colliers (oversize), 1907 August (Box 73)
    - Clippings, Doris Duke, 1937; 1964-1990; 1999 (Box 66)
      Includes articles about Doris Duke's renovation efforts in Newport, RI
    - Clippings, miscellaneous, 1898-1915; 1924-1934 (Box 66)
    - Clippings, miscellaneous, 1947; 1960-1998; undated (Box 66)
    - Diploma from Eastman National Business College 1875, September 8 (Oversize-folder 6)
    - Passports: James B., Nanaline, and Doris Duke, 1923 (Box 66)
    - Proof for cast of commemorative plate: Signing of The Duke Endowment, undated (after 1924) (Box 74)
    - Scrapbook on James B. Duke: Business, philanthropic, family, undated (Box 66)
      Chiefly photographs and clippings related to business undertakings, including copies of photographs from James B. Duke's 1923 trip with Aluminum Company of America (Alcoa) executives to the Saguenay River in Quebec, Canada.
    - Tailoring dimensions and shoe pattern, James B. Duke, circa 1909-1923; undated (Box 67)
  - Printed Material, 1919-1982; undated; 6
    Arranged chronologically by printed or estimated publication date.
    - Biographical statements about James B. Duke, 1952-1982; undated (Box 67)
    - Biography of Eugene Healan Thomason, with description of J.B. Duke's patronage, undated (Box 67)
    - Memorials: Address Commemorating the Ninth Anniversary of The Duke Endowment, given by George G. Allen, Greenville, SC, 1933 (Box 67)
    - Memorials: "In Memoriam, James B. Duke," Alumni Register of Duke University, 1925 November (Box 67)
    - Memorials: Resolution: Death of Benjamin N. Duke: The Duke Endowment (presentation copy), 1929 (Box 67)
    - Memorials: Resolution: Death of Benjamin N. Duke: Duke Power Company (presentation copy), 1929 (Box 67)
    - Memorials: Resolution: Death of James B. Duke: The Duke Endowment (presentation copies), 1925 (Box 67)
    - Memorials: Resolution: Death of James B. Duke: Furman University (presentation copies), 1926 (Box 67)
    - Memorials: Resolution: Death of James B. Duke: Piedmont and Northern Railway Company (presentation copy), 1926 (Box 67)
    - Memorials: Program: Duke University: Memorial service for James B. Duke, 1925 October (Box 67)
    - Memorials: Program: Duke University: Annual memorial services, 1939 (Box 67)
    - Memorials: Program: Johnson C. Smith University, 89th Anniversary ("Saluting James Buchanan Duke..."), 1956 (Box 67)
    - Duke family history (oversize), undated (Box 73)
      Possibly publication proof for chapter on the Duke family in "Annals of American Families" (see Correspondence Series, 1917)
    - Potvin, Damase and W. O'Farrell, The Saguenay River trip: historical, legendary, descriptive [travel literature], Quebec, 1923 (Box 67)
    - Free, E. E., "The New Empire of the Saguenay" (reprint), 1926 (Box 67)
    - Teague, Katherine, "A Twentieth Century King Midas?: James B. Duke", circa 1928-1929 (Box 67)
    - "In A Carolina Forest" [Duke University], in Time, 1931 April 27 (Box 67)
    - Cash, W.J., "Buck Duke's University," in The American Mercury, 1933 September (Box 67)
    - Rickey, James W. [Aluminum Company of America], "Hydro Power for the Production of Aluminum," copied from Transactions of the Electrochemical Society, Vol. LXX, 1936 (Box 67)
    - Saguenay River Developments, undated (1948 or later) (Box 67)
    - Watson, E.A. and L. McW., "Lynchburg Tobacco Imprints," in The Iron Worker, 1950-1951 (Box 67)
      Article describes the history of the Bonsack Machine Company and its manufacture by the Lynchburg Iron Foundry, as well as the use of the machines by W. Duke, Sons and Co. and the American Tobacco Company
    - Hunt, Roy A [Aluminum Company of America], "The Aluminum Pioneers," Newcomen Society in North America, 1951 (Box 67)
    - Fox, John W., Outline of Development of Duke Power Company, 1952 (Box 67)
    - Towe, Kenneth C. [American Cyanamid Co.], "William Brown Bell," Newcomen Society in North America, 1953; "Remarks Before the NY Society of Security Analysts," 1955 (Box 67)
    - The American Tobacco Story [American Tobacco Company], 1962 (Box 67)
    - Durden, Robert F., Troubled Legacy: James B. Duke's Bequest to His Cousins (reprint), 1973 (Box 67)
- Pictures, 1870s-1960s and undated (bulk 1910s); 7
  The Pictures Series contains photographs of James B. Duke, Washington Duke, Benjamin N. Duke, and their immediate and extended families; photographs and sketches of properties and houses including Duke Farms (James B. Duke's Somerville, NJ estate), Duke's mansion in Charlotte, NC, the Duke Homestead, and Fairview (Washington Duke's home in Durham, NC); pictures from the album of Mildred Karnes Baldwin, first cousin once removed of James B. Duke; and various photographs related to business interests of James B. Duke.
  - Dailey, Bettie Roney (Mrs. John C.), undated (Box 68)
  - Duke, Angier B. (oversize), circa 1923 (Box 73)
  - Duke, Artelia Roney, portrait, undated; 1 items (Box 68)
    Image of Artelia Roney Duke portrait at Elon University, Elon, NC, reproduced as part of memorial article "Artelia Roney Duke: an Appreciation"
  - Duke, Benjamin N.: The Misses Selby studio portrait, circa 1900s-1910s (oversize); Underwood and Underwood studio portrait, circa 1910s-1920s (oversize), circa 1900s-1920s (Box 73)
  - Duke, Benjamin N.: Underwood and Underwood studio portrait, circa 1910s-1920s (oversize), circa 1900s-1920s (Box 74)
  - Duke, Benjamin N. and Sarah P. with family, 1890s; circa 1916 (Box 68)
    Benjamin N. Duke, Sarah P. Duke, Angier B. Duke, Cordelia Duke Biddle and infant Angier Biddle Duke (circa 1916); Portrait of Sarah P. Duke with young Mary Lillian Duke [Mary Duke Biddle], Angier B. Duke, and unidentified woman (1890s); Benjamin N. Duke, possibly Ms. McCabe of Petersburg, Sarah P. Duke, James B. Duke, Angier B. Duke, and Mary Lillian Duke [Mary Duke Biddle] (1890s)
  - Duke, Doris, christening the Liberty Ship SS James B. Duke, 1944; 1 photographs (Box 68)
  - Duke, James B.: Eastman Business College student, circa 1870s; 1934; 3 photographs (Box 68)
    Portrait of James B. Duke while he was a student at Eastman Business College, Poughskeepie, New York; includes copy of 1934 letter from R.L. Flowers to W.R. Perkins describing the photograph.
  - Duke, James B., circa 1910s-1920s; undated (Box 68)
    Various prints of Underwood and Underwood portrait
  - Duke, James B.: Underwood and Underwood studio portraits (front and profile) (oversize), circa 1910s-1920s (Box 73)
  - Duke, James B.: Painting by John DaCosta, circa 1910s-1920s (Box 68)
    Black and white photographs of painting
  - Duke, James B.: Engraving (with signature), circa 1905 (Box 68)
  - Duke, James B. and Benjamin N., 1924; undated (Box 68)
    Studio portrait of J.B. Duke and B.N. Duke (circa 1910s-1920s); Photographs of the brothers on the boardwalk in Atlantic City, New Jersey (1924)
  - Duke, James B., Benjamin N., Washington and others: Erwin, NC barbecue, circa 1902-1904 (Box 68)
    Various prints of two group photographs at an Erwin, NC gathering. Individuals pictured include: Benjamin N. Duke, Washington duke, James B. Duke, T.J. Walker, A.B. Carrington, J.S. Cobb, John C. Angier, A.G. Carr, W.A. Erwin, J. Edward Stagg, Frank Tate, E.S. Yarbrough, Captain Lemon, F.L. Fuller. Dates vary across copies of photograph.
  - Duke, James B., Benjamin N. and others near Erwin, North Carolina, circa 1902-1903 (Box 68)
    Group crossing the bridge over the Cape Fear River near Duke [Erwin], NC in buggies. Pictured are James B. Duke, Benjamin N. Duke, F.L. Fuller, W.A. Erwin, and J.S. Cobb. Dates vary across copies of photograph.
  - Duke, James B. and Doris, 1919; 1 photograph and 1 photographic postcard (Box 68)
    Includes one photographic postcard from Doris Duke to Benjamin N. Duke, postmarked 1919. Postcard reads "With my best love Doris."
  - Duke, James Buchanan and Dula, Caleb C., undated; 2 photographs (Box 68)
    Two still images captured from motion picture reel filmed at Dula's Yonkers, New York home.
  - Duke, James B. with family and friends, Myers Park, Charlotte, North Carolina, undated; 21 photographs (Box 68)
    Photographs of social gatherings at the Duke mansion in Myers Park, Charlotte, NC. See also Mildred Karnes Baldwin album.
  - Duke, James B., fishing trip, Carteret Lodge near Newport, North Carolina, undated (Box 68)
    Photographs feature James B. Duke, unidentified companions and lodge staff.
  - Duke, James B., funeral, 1925; 2 folders (Box 68)